Hello friends, last week I had a client who wanted to
renew his car policy with us.
He called and said that his father had
also booked his insurance directly from the company's total form, that is,
one car and two
insurance policies. In this case, one of his policies will have to be
cancelled. In today's
video, we will find a solution to this problem:
what is the process of cancelling an insurance policy?
In which cases can you cancel an insurance policy?
How much time does this entire process take? How much money is deducted before the
rest is credited to your account.
Hello friends, my name is Harminder Singh,
and you are watching DSP Solutions'
YouTube channel. Let's talk about those questions
which you will neither
find in the insurance company's policy tree nor will you see
them in their TV ads. But these are
small problems that common people like you and me face in
Delhi. If you are
new to the channel, please subscribe to the channel
and press the bell icon and
set the notifications to more. So, let's
know about policy cancellation. Now
friends, first of all, it tells us that we have to
cancel the policy.  Why do we have to get it done?
What are those things and how
can we cancel it from that point? First of all,
suppose there is a mistake in our policy, the
value of our vehicle has decreased,
we were looking for an add-on but could not get it,
and we booked it through follow-up and
paid for it, the police came to us, then
in that case you have to book another policy
with updated details and updated advance
and you
can cancel the old one positively. The second case is,
suppose you are selling your vehicle
and you do not want to
transfer your insurance policy on the next Monday, then in that case also you can apply
for policy cancellation and you
can also keep your NCVT certificate with you. The
third question comes friends, as
I told them that it may not be in your knowledge
and if two cards are booked
because there is one vehicle, the coverage will be given by one, then there is
no use in booking two, one of them
could be prostate cancer, friends, now let's talk about what is the
complete process of cancellation, i.e.
What is the process to cancel it,
for that first of all you have to
apply in the insurance company, you have to
select the insurance company whose policy you want to cancel, then
what are you saying for cancellation, you can directly
visit the branch, you can
tell your insurance advisor, you can make a
toll free call, to know the toll free number
you
can get all the company toll free numbers by clicking on the i button, along with
this, the easiest way I
think is through an email, now you
can do this last, you
can also get it done by opening your advisor, now the format of the email will be
complete, in the
subject line of the mail itself you have to write that
cancellation of policy number, the points which are the
number, you have to mention that, then
in the subject you have to write what is your result, you have made a
mistake in any of your previous policies or you have made a
purchase from people by mistake
or you want to sell the car, hence
along with that you have to
also mention all the related matters  Now
what are the documents that you have to attach? See, for selling the vehicle, the
Siemens company
can ask you for different documents, but if there is
any mistake in your policy or
someone has been removed from other policies without your knowledge, the
documents for that are only those two
processes, one is the one which is to be cancelled
and the other is the old nail polish which will continue,
you have to attach the policies of both of them,
along with the payment details in your vehicle's RC
plus the
account in which this money will be credited,
that ₹1 of refund has to be shared by Pushpendra, till now there is
no standard procedure for this, every company has its own president of IRDA, the
documents that you will need have been mentioned
and that method will be almost the same for every company that
you
can get this work done through email, so friends, in this way
you have to apply through this ma'am, now
when will you get the reply to this mail and how much time will it take for
your policy to get cancelled,
see, it will not be within 1 to 2 days but within 2448
hours  Inside, the report comes and an
acknowledgement is sent that I have been received by them,
after that they give you a week's time to
report in this, within a week
they will not give you any reply from you,
they need this dish allotment,
they ask for additional information from you and within the fourth day
this policy is cancelled and the money is in your
hands,
in some cases it happens that due to technical reasons
or
due to pendency of any document information, it can get
extended by two-four days, but the send
time is that almost within four days
and cancel it, ok the money comes to your account,
now the money has come in your account,
but how will you calculate this, how much money will
come in our account daily, from what you have
cancelled from the policy, how much money will come to
yours, now it is only ₹50 for this, if the
time of your policy has started, the full
coverage time has started, then
after that, whatever you have used
in the same countries, your mood will be off
in the program, but suppose your
policy  It expires after 10 days and you
renewed it today and during the same time you had to cancel it,
say so, then in that case no
money will be refunded to you and if you do it
after the same period starts, then let me
explain it to you by way of example,
suppose you have a 12 months policy of one year, through
which you get 3 months, you have
used your points, after that you
saw that some other policy is also running with you, of
which you did not have any, then
one of them will not only be able to cancel, then the
money of that 3 months, which was
taken from you in the same countries for 12 months, will be
deducted in the same proportion for the 3 months and will
come to your account, friends, I have
tried my best that I will be able to tell you the major
information about policy cancellation,
but there can be a lot of doubts, a lot of
questions can be asked related to this and this is the thing that
I especially like about YouTube that it has a
comment section, please comment your doctor
skills, I will definitely try to help
you  Let me clear your doubts,
friends, with the hope that you remain happy and
healthy, we will meet next week with more important
information. Till then, take
care of yourself and stay happy. Thank you
a minute ago.
[Music]